Bugs are super gross!
(大蛇丸)うわぁ～ 虫 気持悪い！
There are bugs here too!
ここにも虫～！
Bugs! Everywhere!
(大蛇丸)虫だらけ～！
Good job.
What happened to the ones
who haven't returned?
(シノ)ご苦労だった。
What's up with these bugs?
まだ戻ってきていないやつは
どうした？
Chase 'em away, Tsukune!
I can't stand bugs.
(ツクネ)なんだよ この虫！
(ミブナ)さっさと追い払ってよ ツクネ
虫苦手だし 私。
But these aren't ordinary bugs!
(サンショ)でも なんか この虫
普通のと違うんだって。
Cut it out, you guys.
It's because those insects
are my friends.
お前たち やめるんだ。
なぜなら
その虫は俺の仲間だからだ。
– These bugs are your friends?
What's up with this old guy?
(３人)虫が仲間？
Those kids!
何言ってんの
このおじさん。
This period is for
extracurricular work.
(イルカ)まったくあいつら
課外授業中だってのに→
Where did they go?
– Wow! Amazing!
Cool!
どこ行ったんだ？
(ツクネたち)おお すげえ！
I've never seen
an Insect User before!
They'd be a huge hit at a party!
かっけえな 兄ちゃん！
蟲使いなんて
初めて見たぞ！
No way... The party would be
crawling with bugs.
ちょっとした宴会とかで使ったら
大ウケだって！
It seems you don't like insects.
ムリムリ
宴会が虫だらけになるし！
However,
if you keep living with them,
虫は嫌いなようだな。
you become quite attached to them.
しかし 共に暮らしていると
かわいくなるもんだぞ。
Y-You're right... They're kinda cute.
I wanna try too!
た たしかに
ちょっとかわいいし。
Do you think you want to
become an Insect User?
Not gonna happen. This guy wants to
become the future Hokage.
俺もやってみてえ！
蟲使いに
なってみたいと思うか？
それはないって こいつ
将来 火影になりたいんだって。
The Hokage?
I wanna surpass Naruto Uzumaki
as a shinobi.
火影に？
I see. Well, if you want to
surpass Naruto,
うずまきナルトを超えるような
忍になりてえと思ってさ。
you'll have to become the Hokage.
You think so too?
そうか ナルトを超えるなら
火影にならなければな。
Then I guess while I'm at it,
I'll become the Hokage too.
やっぱり
そう思うし？
I know someone else who wants to
become the Hokage.
じゃあ ついでに
火影にもなるか。
But kid, you're the top contender.
俺も 火影になりたい
というやつを知っている。
It's because I don't know anyone
who says he'll become the Hokage
しかし 少年
お前がいちばん大物だ。
as an afterthought.
Right? See I'm the top contender!
なぜなら ついでで→
You just talk big!
火影を目指したやつを
俺は知らん。
Shut up! You just watch me
ten years from now!
やっぱそう思うだろ
俺は大物だ！
Are you aiming to become
the Hokage too?
(サンショ)でかいこと
言ってるだけだって。
No, I never gave it a thought.
(ツクネ)うるせえ！
10年後を見てろよ！
So, you wanted to become
an Insect User?
兄ちゃんも
火影 目指してんのか？
Yeah... that's right.
いや 俺は
考えたことはない。
What's necessary
to realize a dream?
じゃあ
蟲使いになりたかったの？
I want to take that first step
as soon as I can!
ああ そうだな。
夢を叶えるためには
まず何が必要なんだ？
The first step in realizing
your dream is...
Hey, what time is it?
俺も早く第一歩を
踏み出したいんだよ。
Uh-oh! We forgot about class!
夢を叶えるための
第一歩か。
You'd better hurry back.
And do your best to surpass Naruto.
ねえ 時間 大丈夫だし？
やっべ
課外授業なの忘れてたって！
Yeah! I'm gonna reach my dream,
just like you Big Bro!
See ya!
急いで戻るがいい。
頑張って
ナルトを超えるんだな。
おお 兄ちゃんみてえに
夢を叶えるよ じゃあな！
Dream... huh?
kara no kokoro wo terasu mono wa nani?
What brightens up an empty heart?
夢か…。
sakebi tsuzukeru hikari todoku made
I will keep on singing until the light reaches you
falling through the cracks kurayami e ochiteku
Falling through the cracks, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me the story of your life mada michi no tochuu
Tell me the story of your life, We're still on our way
anata o watashi wa zettai akiramenai
I will never give up on you
osaerarenai shoudou nanigenai hibi wa aijyou
Urges I can't suppress, I live for the ordinary days
natsukashii kaze ni furimukeba itsud
When I turn my cheek to a nostalgic wind
emo anata no koe ga suru yo
I always hear your voice
underdog wa wander around
Underdog will Wander around
mawari michi shitemo nigeru yori mashi yo
Even if I take the long way around,
it's better than running away
jibun de jibun o shinjirare nakucha dare wo shinjiru no?
If I can't learn to believe in myself,
then who can I believe in?
hikari ni sono te kazase
Hold up your hand to the light
shining through the clouds kurayami e ochiteku
Shining through the clouds, Falling into the darkness
anata no sono te o zettai hanasanai
I will never let go of your hand
tell me what is on your mind hateshinai yume wo
Tell me what is on your mind,
Chasing the never ending dream
oikake bokura wa zettai akiramenai
We will never give up
kotae no nai jinsei ni kujike sou ni naru kedo
Discouraged by a life without answers, but I...
don’t give it up! keep it up! turn it upside down!
Don't give it up! Keep it up! Turn it upside down!
待たせて すまん。
kokoro wa tsunagatteru yo tatoe tooku hanaretemo
Our hearts will always be connected,
no matter how far apart we may be
(キバ)遅えぞ シノ
で どうだった？
tomo ni tomo ni ikiteyukou
Let's share this life together
やはり 皆 すでに
結婚祝いを入手しつつあるようだ。
The                          Last Mission
そうか 俺たちも
そろそろ決めないとな。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
なあ シノ カカシ先生は
これを任務だって言ってたよな？
You're late, Shino!
So? How'd it go?
It seems just about everyone's
gotten their wedding gift.
カカシ先生も みんなも→
あえて そういう
言い方してるのはわかる。
Oh yeah? I guess we'd better
decide soon too.
でもな 俺はこれを
本当の任務だと考えてるんだ。
Hey, Shino...
Kakashi Sensei said
this was a mission, right?
俺たち八班の
最後の任務だってな。
I understand why Kakashi Sensei and
the others are putting it that way.
八班最後の任務。
ヒナタが結婚すりゃ
今までどおり→
But to me,
this is a serious mission.
俺たちが一緒に活動することは
なくなっちまうだろ？
It's our final mission as Team 8.
ああ。
そうだな。
Team 8's final mission...
俺だって 次の火影になることを
視野に入れて→
Once Hinata gets married,
we won't get to work together
like the way we used to, right?
そろそろ本気を出さなきゃ
いけないしよ。
いつまでも
シノに構ってらんねえ。
Yes...
ああ
そういうことにしておこう。
That's true...
And I have to get serious
そういうことにしとく
ってなんだよ！
if I intend on becoming
the next Hokage.
すまん… とにかく→
これが ヒナタのために
俺たちができる→
I can't keep relying on you.
八班としての最後の任務
というわけだな。
Yeah, let's keep it that way.
What do you mean by that?!
そういうことだ。
問題は何を贈るか だよな。
Sorry.
In any case, this is for Hinata,
our last mission as Team 8...
(３人)う～ん。
(紅)ヒナタに贈り物ねえ。
Right?
俺たちからの
お祝いとして→
Right.
The question is...
what do we get them?
ヒナタと ナルトが喜ぶものって
何ですかね？
– Hmm...
(ミライ)赤キバ！ 赤キバとキバ丸！
A gift for Hinata, huh?
まざってる
まざってるんだよなぁ。
It's gonna be from us
to Hinata and Naruto.
What would make them happy?
勘弁してくれよ ミライ。
(紅)フフ お茶じゃなく→
Akakiba!
Akakiba and Kibamaru!
のんびり焼酎でも
飲みたくなってくるわね。
You're mixing up the names...
ああ そうそう
お酒といえば→
Give me a break, Mirai...
あなたたち
こういう話は知ってる？
Rather than hot tea, I feel like
relaxing with some shochu.
昔 森の千手一族には→
結婚祝いに 蜂蜜酒を贈る
習慣があったそうよ。
Oh, that's right.
Speaking of alcohol,
have you heard about this story?
はるか昔
ハチの巣に雨水がたまって→
Back in the day,
the Senju Clan had a custom of
偶然 生まれた不思議な水を→
giving honey wine
as a wedding gift.
森で暮らしていた千手一族が
みつけたものが→
蜂蜜酒の始まりと言われているの。
Long ago, the Senju Clan
who lived in the forest
滋養強壮によい
貴重なお酒だから→
discovered an unusual liquid
that was produced by chance
from rainwater
that collected in beehives.
古くから めでたいときに
ふるまわれてきたものなのよ。
And that was
the start of honey wine.
蜂蜜酒ならば 薬にもなるし
料理にも使えるはずだ。
It was a nourishing, yet rare wine.
And since the olden days,
ヒナタなら うまく使えるはず。
it's been served only during
auspicious occasions.
案外 喜ぶかもな。
Honey wine could be used
as a medicinal tonic
ヒナタとナルトが
密なる日々を送ることを→
as well as for cooking.
Hinata would find
some good uses for it.
祈る意味にもなるだろう。
She may appreciate
something like this!
つまんねえダジャレだな。
ヒナタが聞いたら あきれるぞ。
And it conveys the wish
that Hinata and Naruto
spend their days in sweetness.
That's a cheesy joke.
あなたたちが
ヒナタのいないところで➡
Hinata wouldn't find it funny!
盛り上がるなんて
不思議だけど→
きっと すぐに慣れるわね。
It's strange seeing you two
so lively without Hinata...
それで その蜂蜜酒は
どこで手に入るんです？
But I guess you'll get used to it.
(紅)
空区だって聞いたことがあるわ。
Anyway, where do we find
this honey wine?
正確には そこに住んでいる
養蜂家がつくっているって話よ。
"SORAKU"
I heard there's a place
called Soraku.
あなたたちなら
人捜しはオハコでしょ？
And it seems the beekeeper
who lives there makes honey wine.
よし 決まりだな。
その養蜂家という人物を
捜し出すぞ。
Finding people
is your specialty, right?
バイバイ！ キバ丸 赤キバ。
Okay, it's decided.
Let's go find this beekeeper.
八班最後の任務だ。
いくぜ お前ら！
(赤丸)ワン！
Bye bye, Kibamaru! Akakiba!
最後の任務か。
It's Team 8's final mission!
Let's go, guys!
Our last mission, huh?
寂しい場所だ。
おまけに辛気臭い場所だぜ。
(モモ)辛気臭くて悪かったニャ。
What a desolate place...
And it's pretty depressing too.
(シノ/キバ)なっ!?
ウーッ！
Sorry, it's so depressing, meow.
(モモ)その額当て 木ノ葉の忍だニャ？
犬くさい 虫くさい 犬そのもの。
Judging from your headbands,
you're Hidden Leaf shinobi, meow?
まったく
ろくでもないやつらだニャ。
You reek of dogs, you reek of bugs,
and you're a real dog.
忍猫か？
Damn it, what a sorry bunch, meow.
俺たちは 空区にいるという
養蜂家を捜しているだけだ。
A ninja cat?!
We're looking for a beekeeper
who lives in a place called Soraku.
怪しい者ではない。
ニャ！ とても怪しいニャ。
We're not sketchy guys.
お前らに教えることなどないニャ。
Meow, you're totally sketchy, meow!
ってことは
養蜂家の居場所を知ってんだな？
I've got nothing to tell you, meow.
So that means you know where
this beekeeper is, right?
よし 捕まえて締め上げてから
聞き出すってのでもいいな。
Okay, how about we catch it
and get the info out of it?
いくぜ 赤丸！
ワン！
愚かな人間どもニャ。
Let's do it, Akamaru!
キャイン！
あっ ちょっ うわっ…。
Dumb humans, meow!
キャン キャン キャン…。
あっ くぅ…。
H-Hey!
虫寄せの術。
Insect Summoning Jutsu!
あ～ 助かった。
ナメやがって クソ猫が！
こうなったら…。
Saved!
You're gonna mess around with us?!
ジャジャン！ ほれ。
Fine, then...
Tadah!
何だニャ これは？
Here.
What is this?!
こりゃ イヌハッカだ。
マタタビと似た成分が入ってる。
This is catnip.
It's very similar to silver vine.
どうだ？
こいつは無視できねえだろ？
Well?
Can't ignore it, can you?
ぐぬぬニャ…。
Damn it...
こんな犬くさいやつに捕まるなど
プライドが許さないのニャ！
My pride would never forgive me
if I got caught by someone
who reeks like a dog.
あっ… おい！
ネコババすんじゃねえ このクソ猫が！
Hey!
Don't steal it!
You damn cat!
(タマキ)モモ！
Momo!
ニャニャニャ…。
なんですか あなたたち!?
うちのモモを追いかけて。
Who are you guys?
How dare you chase after my Momo!
あの忍猫の使い手か。
Must be that ninja cat's master.
気をつけろ キバ 赤丸。
Be careful, Kiba, Akamaru!
へぇ～ モモっていうんですか。
Oh... her name's Momo?
ハハッ 奇遇ですね。
うちの犬も赤丸っつうんですよ。
Fancy that...
My dog's name is Akamaru.
キ… キバ？
ク～ン。
K-Kiba?
もしかして うちの猫が→
By any chance,
was my cat rude to you?
失礼なことをしましたか？
すみません。
I'm so sorry.
No, no... She's a cute ninja cat.
いやいや
かわいい忍猫ちゃんですね。
キッ ついさっきまで→
Just a minute ago,
you called me a "damn cat."
クソ猫って言ってたのは
どこの誰だニャ。
My name is Tamaki.
私はタマキと言います。
俺はキバ。
I'm Kiba...
This is my ninja hound, Akamaru.
この赤丸は俺の忍犬です。
You're a ninja hound user?!
忍犬使いなんですか!? すごい！
Amazing!
いや まあ ヘヘッ それほどでも。
Oh, it's nothing.
Although... I'm on the inside track
to become the next Hokage.
あ ほら
すごいって言っても あれだぜ？
俺なんか 次期火影の内定を
もらってるって程度の話だから。
The next Lord Hokage?!
次期火影様？ すごい すごい！
いや～ ヘヘヘ。
That's really amazing!
Nah...
ク～ン。
But what is
an important person like you
doing in a place like this?
でも そんなすごい方が
なんで こんなところに？
Actually...
Actually... we're looking for
a beekeeper who lives in Soraku.
実はだな…。
実は この空区にいるっていう
養蜂家を捜してたんだけどよ。
Would you like me to guide you
part of the way?
よかったら
途中まで案内しましょうか？
You know him?
That would be great!
知ってんのか
そりゃ ありがてえ。
Right, Shino?
なっ シノ。
ハァ。
He lives in the bamboo grove
beyond here.
この先の竹やぶに
住んでいるはずです。
You probably
won't be able to find him.
どうせ
お前らには見つけられないニャ。
Even cats get lost
in this grove, meow.
We're shinobi!
猫ですら迷う竹やぶニャ。
We won't get lost.
俺たちは忍だぜ 迷わねえよ。
Well then, be careful.
Yeah! Thanks!
それじゃあ お気をつけて。
おう ありがとな。
Yes, I know.
あぁ わかっている。
Intruders...
侵入者だ。
First, I'll track him with my nose.
まずは 俺の鼻で捜すからよ。
And if I find him,
send in your insects.
見つけたら
お前の虫を飛ばして… ハクション！
That girl might be
talking about us.
ヘッ あの子が
噂してるのかもしれねえな。
Are you in love with her?
Huh?! Are you crazy?!
惚れたのか？
はぁ？
It's nothing like that!
バッカ おめえ 違えよ！
This is a crucial time if I'm gonna
become the Hokage!
火影になるためには
大事な時期だぞ。
I have no time to fall in love!
女に惚れるなんて ねえよ！
わかりやすいやつだな。
You're easy to read.
Huh? What did you say?
あ？ なんだって？
Nothing. I just said I envy you.
いや お前がうらやましいと
言ったんだ。
Huh? Really?
え？ ヘヘッ そうか？
And I have to get serious
((俺だって次の火影になることを
視野に入れて→
if I intend to become
the next Hokage.
(そろそろ本気を
出さなきゃいけないしよ))
Kiba always talks big, and maybe
I viewed him with indifference...
《大きなことを言うキバを
俺はどこかで→
冷ややかに見ていたところが
あったかもしれない。
However...
What's necessary
to realize a dream?
しかし…》
((夢を叶えるためには
まず何が必要なんだ？
I want to take that first step
as soon as I can!
俺も早く
第一歩を踏み出したいんだよ。
The first step in
realizing your dream...
(夢を叶えるための第一歩か…))
Who am I to criticize anyone?
《人のことを とやかく言える
立場ではないな》
Once Hinata gets married,
we won't get to work together
like the way we used to, right?
((ヒナタが結婚すりゃ→
今までどおり
俺たちが一緒に活動することは➡
"The way we used to," huh?
(なくなっちまうだろ？))
《今までどおりでは
なくなる… か》
Kiba!
Hey, Kiba!
キバ？ おい キバ！ どこだ？
Where are you?!
Really? You guys don't know either?
This is definitely someone's jutsu...
そうか
お前たちでもわからないか。
これは確実に何者かの術だな。
Yellow jackets?!
スズメバチか…。
What is this jutsu?!
なんだ この術は？
うっ！
You belong to the Aburame Clan
of Hidden Leaf Village.
木ノ葉の油女一族だな。
Correct.
そのとおりだ。
You're skilled to be able to
deceive me...
この私を欺くとは
たいしたやつだ。
But how?
The poison should have...
だが なぜだ？ 確かに毒は…。
The poison got me...
But it's not a problem.
毒はくらった。 だが問題ない。
It's because this amount of poison
won't kill me.
なぜなら この程度の毒では
俺は死なないからだ。
Well now, it's my loss.
It can't be helped.
まいったな。 私の負けだ。
まあ仕方ない。
I'm proud to die by the hand of
an Insect User of your caliber.
ここまで腕のいい蟲使いに
殺されるのであれば 本望だ。
No, hold on.
I don't want your life.
いや 待て。 俺の目当ては
お前の命ではない。
I want your honey wine.
蜂蜜酒だ。
え？
Thank you, how much do I owe you?
I don't want money.
You can take it. It means nothing.
すまない いくらだ？
カネはいらん。
I see...
持っていても意味はないからな。
Now, if you can tell me
the road back, I'd be grateful.
そうか ついでに→
There is no road.
帰り道を教えてもらえると
ありがたいのだが。
What do you mean?
帰り道などない。
Exactly what I said.
どういうことだ？
そのままの意味だ。
This bamboo grove is surrounded by
something like a barrier.
この竹やぶは
結界のようなもので覆われている。
Once you step inside,
there's no way out.
You'll continue to wander through
an endless fog... that is all...
一度踏み入れたら出られない。
That's the kind of jutsu this is.
見渡すかぎりの霧の中で
どこまでも迷い続ける。
What?!
これは そういう術なんだ。
なんだと？
I'm sorry to tell you that
this jutsu cannot be broken.
Even if you kill me...
≪残念だがこの術は解けない。
What do you mean?!
Originally, this mist contained
仮に
私を殺しても解けないだろう。
a special component
meant to lead people astray.
どういうことだ？
I incorporated a little of it
into my jutsu formula...
≪この霧には もともと→
人を惑わす
特殊な成分が含まれていた。
私は それをほんの少し利用して→
But that can't be why
you can't break the jutsu?
術式に組み込んだだけなんだ。
No...
But, the nasty thing
about this jutsu is...
それだけであれば
解けないことはないだろう？
... that it takes the doubt inside of
its victims and turns it into fog,
≪ああ しかし
この術の厄介なところは→
making it thicker and thicker...
What?!
Haven't you noticed?
かかった者の持つ
迷いが霧を生み→
This bamboo grove
makes people lose their way...
濃くしているということだ。
and when the jutsu is used,
なにっ！
a thicker fog
confuses them even more.
≪気づいたか？
この竹やぶは人を迷わせる。
In other words,
this jutsu has no effect on someone
who has no doubts.
そこで術にかかると→
更なる迷いの霧に
さまようこととなる。
So... you're saying I have doubts?
逆にいえば
迷うことがない者は→
Yeah! I'm gonna reach my dream,
just like you!
術にもかからないということだ。
Once Hinata gets married,
俺が… 迷ってるだと？
we won't be working together
the way we used to, right?
((おお！
兄ちゃんみてえに夢を叶えるよ。
It's strange seeing you two
so lively without Hinata...
ヒナタが結婚すりゃ 今までどおり→
俺たちが一緒に活動することは
なくなっちまうだろ？
But I guess you'll get used to it.
I understand...
あなたたちが
ヒナタのいないところで→
盛り上がるなんて
不思議だけど→
(きっと すぐに慣れるわね))
I've been questioning
how to live as a shinobi
そういうことか…。
after Team 8 disbands
when Hinata gets married.
ヒナタが結婚し
八班がなくなることで→
To be together always,
with my friends in Team 8.
忍として どう生きるべきか→
That was my dream.
俺は わからなくなっていた。
八班の仲間たちで
ずっと過ごし続けることが→
I see...
I was doubting myself...
You and I are alike.
俺の夢だったんだ。
I'm still lost
on this path called life.
そうか… 俺は迷っていたのか。
So, how about it?
There is doubt,
but there is no suffering here.
≪キミも私と同じだ。
I am finally living life now!
私も 人生という名の道に
迷っている。
Your friends understand too!
しかし どうだ!?
It's okay to have doubts...
ここには
迷いはあれど 苦しみはない。
It's not your fault
that you have doubts...
私は 今を生きているんだ！
キミの仲間たちも
わかってくれている。
Kiba... Hinata...
キミは迷っていいんだ。
It's not necessary to move forward.
迷うことは キミの責任ではない！
Abandon it all, and stay here
with your doubts.
If you agree, stay with us...
キバ… ヒナタ…。
C'mon, Shino...
前に進む必要など ない。
すべてを捨てて ここで
ずっと迷っていればいい。
キミさえよければ
私たちと一緒に…。
It's Team 8's final mission!
Let's go, guys!
((さぁ 来いよ！ シノ…))
No...
That's not what... I'm looking for...
((八班最後の任務だ。
いくぜ お前ら！))
What?
What I'm looking for is...
What I'm looking for...
(シノ)違う…。
... is to be with my friend
who keeps moving forward.
俺が求めているのは… 違う。
Not someone who stays
in the same place with me!
なに!?
俺が求めているのは…。
I can't be stuck here like this.
俺が求めているのは→
I have to return to the village
right away.
前へと進む仲間とともに
いることだ。
It's because... I have to attend
an important friend's wedding.
俺に足並みを揃えるやつではない。
俺は こんな所で→
You think you can find
your way out of this fog?
立ち止まっているわけには
いかない。
When you're in so much doubt
about your life?!
急いで里に
帰らなければならない。
Yeah.
なぜなら 大切な友の結婚式に→
To make sure he can walk
his path without worry,
出席しなければならないからだ！
I'm definitely gonna
find my path in life.
この霧から出られると
思っているのか!?
And I have no doubt about that!
お前は
人生に迷っているというのに…。
あぁ あいつらが安心して
己の道に進めるためにも→
An entrance...
俺は 俺の道を 必ず探す。
No, it's the exit.
そのことに もう迷いはない！
So, you were able to see
the path beyond
the guardian deity of travelers.
I see... Then go quickly.
入り口…。
Before you lose the path.
いや 出口だ。
Wait... You just said
you're living life now.
But is that really true?
≪キミには 道祖神の先に
道が見えたのか。
What?
Someone who remains
stuck in the past,
そうか。 早く行くといい。
また 道を失わないうちに…。
and cannot see the future...
Is that really living?
待て！
お前は 今を生きていると言った。
I know people
who live every moment,
だが 本当に そうなのか？
≪なに？
striving as hard as they could to
reach a goal that seems so far...
They're the ones
who are really living life.
(シノ)過去を引きずり→
未来を
見ないようにしている者が→
That's my belief...
本当に 今を生きていると
言えるのだろうか？
I'm shocked.
You're nothing like the quiet man
I thought you were...
俺は知っている…。
You are very passionate
on the inside.
はるか遠い目標のために→
I feel like I'm being lectured
by my teacher.
今 この一瞬を
生き抜こうとしているやつらを。
What are you saying?
あいつらこそが
今を生きている者だ。
Now go.
In time, I will be like you...
俺は そう思う。
意外だったよ。
物静かな男と思っていたが→
ずいぶんと熱い内面を
持っているようだな。
Where have you been?!
教師に説教された気分だ。
You disappeared suddenly!
何を言う…。
Sorry.
However, I got a hold of this.
行くがいい。
私も いずれ キミと同じように…。
Whoa! When did you—!
I was sure you were lost.
Yeah, I was lost.
But I've found my way.
どこ行ってたんだよ シノ！
突然 いなくなりやがって…。
It's because...
Anyway, let's take this home,
Akamaru!
ワン！
すまなかった。
しかし こいつは手に入れたぞ。
What about that girl?
おぉっ！ お前 いつの間に!?
Huh?!
Why are you bringing
that up again?!
てっきり
迷ってたのかと思ったぜ。
Sorry.
Damn it.
あぁ 迷っていた。
Maybe I'll write her.
しかし 今は晴れた。
なぜなら…。
Letters? How unlike you.
とにかく！
これ持って 帰るぞ 赤丸。
Huh? Why?!
There's nothing wrong with letters.
Right, Akamaru?!
ワン！
(シノ)それで あの子はいいのか？
Akamaru, not you too?!
はぁ!? だから なんで また
その話になるんだよ？
Yikes! Bugs again!
すまない。
ったく…。
It's so amazing!
文通からなら ありかもな。
Maybe I'll make my goal to
become an Insect User too.
Yeah...
(シノ)文通か… お前らしくないな。
I'd better get started too,
or I won't become the Hokage.
(キバ)えっ!? なんでだよ？
文通だぞ！ いいだろ？
You're wrong, kid.
なぁ？ 赤丸！
クーン…。
You've already taken that step.
Huh?
赤丸！ お前まで!!
It's because...
(大蛇丸)ヒェーッ！ また 虫が出た!!
Putting your goal into words...
やっぱ すごいって！
... is the first step towards
realizing one's dream.
私も蟲使い
目指してみようかな！
I got it!
あぁ… 俺も
早く 一歩踏み出さないと→
Thanks, Big Bro!
Let's go!
火影になれねえな。
違うぞ 少年。
Tsukune, come on!
Yeah!
お前は すでに踏み出している。
えっ？
なぜなら…。
Iruka Sensei...
You completely won over
those bad kids.
目標を言葉にする。
それこそが夢への第一歩だからだ。
Maybe you should become a teacher.
A teacher?!
It's difficult even for us
to keep up with
そっか！
ありがとうな 兄ちゃん。
mischievous kids like that
year after year.
行くぞ！
You're quite impressive.
ツクネ あんたも来なよ！
おう！
It's not that difficult for me.
(３人)アハハハハ！
It's because...
イルカ先生。
I've always been around...
あの悪ガキどもを
こんなに手懐けるなんて…。
... the bad kids...
"11 MORE DAYS UNTIL THE WEDDING"
kakaeta omou i tokitoshite
Sometimes, the feelings we have
kazoe kirenai itami o
Cause us immense pain
yuzurenai hokori mune ni
We've lived this entire time
imamade ikite kitadarou
With unshakeable pride in our hearts
tatakau koto de mamotte
Defending by fighting
omoigakenaku nakushite
With unexpected losses
kizutsukiai ma nande
We learn as we hurt one another
taisetsu na koto ni kizukudarou
Will we realize what's most important?
koe ga todokanai
My voice cannot reach you
soredemo (soredemo)
Even so
kokoro shinjite iyou
Let's trust our hearts
zenshin zenrei kimi wo mamoru yo
I will protect you with every essence of my being
towa ni sou towa ni
For all eternity
nankaidatte tachiagare yo
Stand up again and again
sono ishi de (sono ishi de)
By your own volition
ungai souten asu wo egaku yo
Don't give in; create a new day
tomo ni sou tomo ni
Together with friends
itsudatte akirameru
Never ever give up
na michi wo hirakou
Let's open up the path
ruru
On and on
The wedding's coming up soon...
What's wrong Kakashi Sensei?
Huh?
I was really happy at first,
教師に向いてるんじゃないか？
but when I think about
the upcoming wedding...
教師？
I haven't finished making
all the rounds to greet people...
俺たちだって いつの時代も→
I haven't pinned down
all of the expenses yet...
ヤンチャな連中を
相手にするのは難しい。
And I'm worried if everyone
will make it or not...
Everything is just
making me so anxious!
たいしたもんだよ。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
俺には そう難しいことじゃ
ありません。
Hidden Leaf Story, The Perfect Day for a Wedding, Part 6: The Whereabouts of the Secret Mission
なぜなら…。
俺の周りには
いつも 問題児がいましたから。
You aren't suffering
from cold feet, are you?
Who, me?!